So now you know enough about Python to be able
那么 现在你对 Python 有了足够的了解
to solve the problem that we started with at the
能够解决我们在这单元一开始提出的问题
beginning of this unit, which the problem of extracting a
关于提取网页中的链接的问题
link from its page. Before we get to the code,
在我们编写代码之前
I want to describe a little more carefully what's going
我想更详细地介绍一下
on in a webpage. So we've talked about strings in
网页到底是怎么回事 我们探讨了关于
Python and all a web page really is, is a
Python 中的字符串和网页真正是什么
long string. When you see a web page in your browser,
它就是一个长字符串 当你在浏览器中看到一个网页
it doesn't look like that. So here's an example web
它看起来并不像一个字符串 这里是一个示例网站
page, one of my favorite XKCD comics. And hopefully, you're
我最喜欢的漫画 XKCD 中的一页 希望你可以
starting to learn enough about Python to appreciate the power
开始对 Python 足够的学习 了解 Python 的力量
of Python to make you fly. Probably the rest of
Python 可以让你飞翔 也许对于漫画
the comic, if you haven't done anything other than using
其余的部分 如果你还没有用过 Python 以外的语言
Python, is a little hard to relate for now. But
现在还有点难以理解
it's making fun of other languages where there's an awful
它是在打趣其他的语言 需要做可怕的大量工作
lot of work to do something simple, like we've seen here,
去完成简单的东西 就像我们这里看到的
just being able to print out a string. But with
只是能打印出一个字符串 但是
Python, we can fly quickly, and you're going to learn to fly
使用 Python 我们就可以快得像飞一样 而且你很快就可以
very quickly in this class. This doesn't lok like just
通过这门课程学会快速飞翔 这并不像仅仅是个
a string. We've seen just a string is a sequence of
字符串 我们之前看到 一个字符串只是一串
characters. When we look at a webpage like this, well
字符的序列 当我们看到这样的网页
we see images. We see buttons. We see some text. We
而且 我们看到图像 我们看到按钮 我们看到一些文字
see things that are links and you can see the
我们看到这些东西 是链接 你可以看到
underlines these are all links. And the browser renders the webpage
下划线 这些都是链接 而浏览器呈现网页
in a way that looks attractive. What actually was
的方式看起来很吸引人 实际上
there though, started just as a stream of text.
那只是一个文本流
If you right-click on the webpage, one of the
如果你在网页上点击一下鼠标右键
options you see is View Page Source. When you click
其中一个菜单就是 查看网页源代码 当你点击
on that, you'll see the actual source code. This is what came into the browser.
这个选项 你会看到实际的源代码 也就是进入浏览器的内容
So, your browser sent a request, the URL is what's shown in the address bar.
你的浏览器发送一个请求 网址就是在地址栏中显示的这个
So, it's sent a request to xkcd.com/355.
那么 它发送一个请求到 xkcd.com/355
It sent that request and this is what came back. What came back is just a stream
它发送了这个请求 这就是返回的内容 返回的就是一个
of text. We can look at that text and some of it is fairly hard to understand.
文本流 我们可以看看这些文本 有一些是相当令人费解的
So what's important is the links. Here's an
所以 重要的是链接 这里有一个
example of a link. So, the link starts with
链接的例子 这个链接以
a tag like this. The language HTML uses these
这样的标签开头 HTML 语言使用这些
angle brackets. And the angle bracket a href equals
尖括号 然后 <a href =
is how we start a link. That's followed by
是我们链接的开头 它后面接着的
a string which is surrounded by double quotes, similarly
一个这样由双引号包围的字符串 同样
to a string in Python. So, we have a
在 Python 中也是一个字符串 所以 我们有一对
double quote. Between the double quotes is a URL. The
双引号 双引号之间是一个 URL (网址)
URL is the way of locating content on the
URL (网址) 是对网页内容定位的方式
web so here we have the URL http colon, that
在这里我们有 URL 的 http:
means it's a web request. We'll talk more in
这意味着它是一个 Web 请求 我们后面将讨论更多
a later class about what http means and the protocols
关于 HTTP 的含义和
used to request web pages. What's important now is, that's a
用于请求网页的协议 现在重要的是 这是一个
location If we open that in a web browser, that will give
地址 如果我们在网页浏览器中打开它 这将给
us another page. What I'm looking at here is the link that
我们打开另一个页面 我在这里看到的
is underneath the text for News/Blag. If we click on that link,
是 News/Blag 的文本下的链接 如果我们点击该链接
that will take us to the page blag.skcd.com. That
将来到这个网址 blag.skcd.com
was the page that we saw in the link
那就是我们看到的链接对应的页面
here it said blad.skcd.com. When we click on the
这里写的 vlad.skcd.com 当我们点击这个
link, that's where we went. So to build our crawler,
链接 我们就去到了这里 因此 构建抓取工具
what we want to do for each webpage, we want
我们希望对每一个网页做的 就是
to find these links in the page. We're going to keep
找到页面中的这些链接 我们要保持
track of those links and we're going to follow them
跟随这些链接 我们要跟着他们
to find more content on the web. This is similar
在网络上找到更多的内容 这类似于
to what someone would do if their browsing. If they're
人们浏览时会做的一样 如果他们
clicking on every link of a page, following all the links
点击页面上的每一个链接 跟随所有
they find, looking at all that content. That's a really good
他们找到的链接 查看所有的内容 这是一个非常
way to waste a horrendous amount of time if you do
浪费时间的方法 如果你自己
that yourself. We're going to build a web crawler that can
这样做的话 我们要建立一个网络爬虫
do that automatically. So our goal is to take the text
可以自动执行 因此 我们的目标是
that came back from a web request, find a link in
从网络请求返回的文本中 找到一个链接
that text, which is going to be a tag that starts
链接以 <a href= 标记开头的
with a href equals and then extract from that
然后从标记后面提取
tag the URL of the webpage that it links to.
可以链接到网页的 URL (网址)
Those are the URLs that we're going to use in
这些 URL 就是我们将要
our crawler to make progress. So by using what we've
在抓取工具中使用的 通过使用我们
learned about strings, and what you've learned about variables,
学到的关于字符串的知识 以及你对变量的了解
you know enough to be able to do that. What
你已经知道了足够多的内容可以完成
we want to do is find the beginning of a tag.
我们要做的就是找到开头的标志
And what the beginning of a tag is this text
开头的标志就是这样的文本
right we're looking for something that matches exactly the a href
我们寻找与 <a href= 这部分完全匹配的内容
equals part. That's what the tags were here they all start
这就是标志 它们都是以
with a href equals. Not all webpages have the same structure. There are lots
<a href= 开头的 并非所有的网页具有相同的结构 还有很多
of other ways to make a tag. The A
其他的方法来进行标记
could be a capital letter for example. There could
例如 A 可以是大写字母 有可能
be more spaces between the a and the href.
a 与 href 之间有更多的空格
The double quote doesn't actually need to be there.
双引号实际上并不需要在那儿
For what we do now, we're going to assume that
对于我们现在要做的 我们假设
all our webpages follow the same structure that we're seeing
我们的所有网页遵循这里看到的相同结构
here. That each link starts with an a h ref
每个链接都以 <a href= 开头
without any funny spaces or anything else. Has an equal,
没有任何可笑的空格或其他任何东西 有一个等号
has a double quote, has the URL following that,
有一个双引号 然后紧跟着 URL (网址)
and then another double quote. So that means we're looking
然后又是一个双引号 也就是说我们正在寻找
for strings like this, we're looking to find the a
类似这样的字符串 我们期待找到
href; that's followed by a double quote. After the double
<a href= 后面跟着一个双引号
quote is the URL. This is what we actually care
双引号后面就是这个网址 这是我们真正关心的
about; we want to find the URLs on the Web page.
我们要找出网页上的 URL
That's followed by a closing double quote and then, there's
这是一个结束双引号 然后 还有
more that closes the tag. And there's lots of other
更多的关闭标记 还有很多其他的
stuff on both sides of this. But this is what
东西在这两侧 但这里才是
we want to do. We want to find the tags that are
我们想要处理的 我们希望找到链接的标记
links and then, within the tags that are links, we
然后在作为链接的标记中 我们
want to find the URLs. So we're going to assume that we
要找到这些网址 因此 我们假设
start with the page contents in a variable. We'll
页面内容为一个变量
call that page, and we're not going to worry today
这个变量叫 page 我们今天不用担心
about how we got those page contents. We're going to
如何得到这些页面内容 我们会
provide a function that does that. For the code
提供一个函数来做到这一点 对于
that you have today, let's going to assume the
今天的代码 让我们假设
page is already initialized. That it contains the content
页面已初始化 它包含一些
of some web page stored as a string and our goal is to find the URL of the first
储存为字符串的网页内容 我们的目标是要找到
link in the page. That's going to involve a couple
页面中的第一个链接的 URL  这将涉及几个步骤
steps. SO what we want to do is find the start
所以我们要做的是找到链接的开头
of the link. We want to find where we have the
我们想找到有
a href equals. We can't just look for the first string
a href= 的地方 我们不能光看第一个
we find, because there's lots of other strings on the
我们找到的字符串 因为页面中还有很多
page that aren't URLs. So I think you know enough to
其他不是 URL 的字符串 我想你已经知道
do that, so we'll make it a quiz. So your goal
怎样做了 所以我们将它作为一次测验
for this quiz is to write some Python code that will
你这个测验的目标是写一些 Python 代码
initialize the variable start link to be the
初始化变量 start_link 的值为
value of the position where the first a
第一个 <a href= 出现的位置
href equals. So the first tag that starts
也就是页面上出现的第一个
a link occurs in page, so you should assume
链接开头的标记 所以你应该假设
that page starts with the content of some
page 的初始值是一些网页的内容
web page, and what we're doing is looking for
也就是我们需要从中查找
the place where the first a href equals
第一个 <a href= 出现的地方
occurs, and that's the first link on the page.
这就是页面上的第一个链接